Guide to the Chauncey Brewster Tinker Manuscript Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- File List, Series I
  - "H"
    - Halliwell-Phillips, J. O. (James Orchard), 1820-1889
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 17 Marine Terrace, Aberystwith, 1863 Aug 25 (Box 8, Folder 351)
        Encloses letter from Henry Huth to Halliwell-Phillipps, 1863 Aug 24
    - Hardy, Duffus, Lady, 1825?-1891
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London (Box 8, Folder 352)
        Accompanied by reproduction of photograph of Hardy
    - Harness, William, 1790-1869
      - 2 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1861, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 353)
    - Harwood, Philip, 1809-1897
      - ALS to Mr. Blackett, London, 1869 Jan 19 (Box 8, Folder 354)
    - Hawkins, Sir Anthony Hope, 1863-1933
      - ALS to Mrs. Riggs, London, 1910 Mar 23 (Box 8, Folder 355)
        Tinker 1183
      - ALS to Mrs. Johnson, 1[8]99 Apr 28 (Box 8, Folder 356)
    - Haydon, Frank Scott, 1822-1887
      - 3 ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, 1861-75 (Box 8, Folder 357)
    - Haydon, Frederick Wordsworth, 1827-1886
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Harrogate, n.y. Dec 16 (Box 8, Folder 358)
    - Hayley, William, 1745-1820
      - AL to Caroline (Stuart) Dawson, n.p., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 359)
        Tinker 1186
      - ALS to Thomas Greene, [Eartham], 1793 Apr 26 (Box 8, Folder 360)
        Tinker 1187
      - ALS to Thomas Greene, [Eartham], 1799 Jan 15 (Box 8, Folder 361)
        Tinker 1188
    - Hazlitt, William, 1778-1830
      - AMS of "Lecture VIII. & last.- On the living Poets", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 362)
        Tinker 1190
      - AMS of the last portion of his essay, Footmen, printed in The New Monthly Magazine, 1830 Sep (Box 8, Folder 363)
        Tinker 1191
      - ALS to Archibald Constable, London, 1818 Jul 28 (Box 8, Folder 364)
        Tinker 1192
    - Heraud, John Abraham, 1799-1887
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, Islington, 1865 Feb 28 (Box 8, Folder 365)
    - Herbert, Auberon Edward William Molyneux
      - ALS to Mr. Simpson, Oxford, [1863] Oct 28 (Box 8, Folder 366)
        Year added in different hand
    - Heseltine, W.
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1850 Nov 7 (Box 8, Folder 367)
    - Hichens, Robert Smythe, 1864-1950
      - ALS to Miss Gye, Canterbury, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 368)
        Accompanied by signature of Hichens and portrait of Hichens
    - Higgins, Matthew James, 1810-1868
      - ALS to Frederick Gye, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 369)
        Accompanied by two portraits of Higgins
    - Hill, Frank Harrison, 1830-1910
      - ALS to Mr. Simpson, London, [187-] (Box 8, Folder 370)
    - Hill, Octavia, 1838-1912
      - ALS to Mr. Cockerell, London, [18]75 Jan 20 (Box 8, Folder 371)
    - Hobbes, John Oliver, 1867-1906
      - ALS to Mrs. Johnson, London, 1896 Feb 9 (Box 8, Folder 372)
    - Hofland, Mrs. (Barbara), 1770-1844
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, London, 1831 Nov 29 (Box 8, Folder 373)
    - Hogg, James (1770-1835)
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, Mount Binger, by Selkirk, 1827 Jun 11
        Bound with Tinker 2318 Tinker 1223
    - Holford, Miss (Margaret), 1778-1852
      - ALS to Mrs. Lewis Goldsmid, Hendon, n.y. Jul 12 (Box 8, Folder 374)
    - Holland, Elizabeth Vassall Fox, Lady, 1770-1845
      - ALS to "Sir Charles", London, [1818] (Box 8, Folder 375)
        Tinker 1225
    - Holmes, Richard Rivington, 1835-1911
      - ALS to the Provost of Eton, London, 1861 Oct 14 (Box 8, Folder 376)
    - Hood, Thomas, 1799-1845
      - AMS of chapter 7 of "Our Family", printed in Hood's Magazine, 1844 Aug (Box 8, Folder 377)
        Tinker 1230
    - Housman, A. E., 1859-1936
      - ANS to an unknown correspondent, Cambridge, 1931 Dec 14 (Box 8, Folder 378)
        Tinker 1241
      - ANS to an unknown correspondent, Cambridge, 1934 Dec 13 (Box 8, Folder 379)
        Tinker 1242
    - Howard, Edward, d. 1841
      - ALS to Mary Ann Haly, London, 1828 Jul 8 (Box 8, Folder 380)
        Rewritten vertically. Accompanied by engraved portrait of Howard.
    - Howard, Frank, 1805-1866
      - ALS to Charles L. Smith, Dorking, 1837 Feb 10 (Box 8, Folder 381)
        Accompanied by printed title page and dedication page of Howard's The Sketcher's Manual.
    - Howard, Henry, 1757-1842
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Donington Rectory, 1839 Apr 21 (Box 8, Folder 382)
    - Hughes, Thomas, 1822-1896
      - ANS to Mrs. Prideaux, London, 1874 Nov 2 (Box 9, Folder 383)
        Tinker 1248
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent (Charles Kingsley?), London, 1874 Sep 8 (Box 9, Folder 384)
        Tinker 1249
    - Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Kensington, n.y. Sep 30 (Box 9, Folder 385)
    - Hunt, Thornton Leigh, 1810-1873
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1863 Dec 10 (Box 9, Folder 386)
        Tinker 1259
      - ALS to William Hepworth Dixon, London, 1869 Jan 26 (Box 9, Folder 387)
    - Huth, Henry, 1815-1878
      - ALS to James Orchard Halliwell-Phillipps, Ewell, Surrey, 1863 Aug 24
        - Tinker 1262
        - See: Box 8, folder 351
  - "J"
    - Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784
      - AMS of prayers, 1759?-1766 (Box 9, Folder 388)
        Tinker 1278
      - AMS of "Repertorium", 1784 Oct 31 (Box 9, Folder 389)
        Tinker 1279
      - AMS of Johnson's last prayer, 1784 Dec 5 (Box 9, Folder 390)
        Tinker 1280
      - ALS to James Boswell, [London], [1774? May 27] (Box 9, Folder 391)
        Tinker 1281
      - ALS to Elizabeth Montagu, London, 1759 Jun 9 (Box 9, Folder 392)
        Tinker 1282
      - ALS to Hester Lynch Piozzi, Inverness, 1773 Aug 28 (Box 9, Folder 393)
        Tinker 1284
      - ALS to Hester Lynch Piozzi, Edinburgh, 1773 Nov 18 (Box 9, Folder 394)
        Tinker 1285
      - ALS to Hester Lynch Piozzi, London, 1780 Jun 12 (Box 9, Folder 395)
        Tinker 1286
      - ALS to Hester Lynch Piozzi, London, 1781 Apr 16 (Box 9, Folder 396)
        Tinker 1287
      - AL fragment, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 397)
        Tinker 1288
      - Engravings and facsimile of portraits (Box 9, Folder 398-401)
    - Johnstone, George, 1730-1787
      - AL (draft) to [James Lowther, 1st Earl of Lonsdale], [1786?] (Box 9, Folder 402)
        Concerning John Wilkes Tinker 1418
  - "K"
    - Keble, John, 1792-1866
      - ALS to Mr. Plumer, Penzance, 1862 Oct 13 (Box 9, Folder 403)
        Inviting him to visit Keble in his new home Tinker 1421
      - ALS to Edward T. Richards, Hursley, 1837 Feb 4 (Box 9, Folder 404)
        Written on the third page of the printed petition: "To His Grace the Lord Archbishop of Canterbury," [from] "the undersigned Presbyters and Deacons, resident in the Archdeaconry of Winchester." Tinker 1422
    - Kelly, Frances Maria, 1790-1822
      - ALS to William H. Murray, Dublin, 1818 Jan 20 (Box 9, Folder 405)
        Tinker 1425
    - Kingsley, Charles, 1819-1875
      - ALS to Captain Coulson, London (Box 9, Folder 406)
      - AMS of a sermon on Matthew ix:32-34, "Preached at Eversley-1852-Morng. of 1st Sunday after Epiphany" (Box 9, Folder 407)
        Tinker 1426
      - AMS (draft) of "Martin's song at Alftruda's wedding", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 408)
        Tinker 1427
      - AMS of a draft of the dedication to Thomas Wright of Hereward the Wake (1866), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 409)
        Tinker 1428
      - ALS to Thomas Carlyle, Clovelly, Bideford, [1849] (Box 9, Folder 410)
        Tinker 1429
      - ALS to John Stuart Mill, Eversley, 1869 Jun 17 (Box 9, Folder 411)
        Tinker 1430
      - ALS to the Rev. Mr. R. Tyndal, Eversley, 1858 Nov 1 (Box 9, Folder 412)
        Tinker 1431
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, Harrow, 1874 Jan 23 (Box 9, Folder 413)
        Tinker 1432
  - "L"
    - Lamb, Charles, 1775-1834
      - AMS of a portion of a list of Coleridge's works, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 414)
        Tinker 1455
      - ALS to Thomas Allsop, London, [1820 Sep 1] (Box 9, Folder 415)
        Tinker 1456
    - Landor, Walter Savage, 1775-1864
      - AMS of "To Aubrey De Vere", 1848 Sep 23 (Box 9, Folder 416)
        Tinker 1459
      - "To Edith Story," autograph manuscript poem, signed and dated, [18]60 Sep 17 (Box 9, Folder 417)
        Tinker 1460
      - ANS to [Richard H. Horne?], n.p., [1844?] (Box 9, Folder 418)
        Tinker 1461
    - Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912
      - ALS to [Chauncey Brewster Tinker], Edinburgh, [19-] Jul 22 (Box 9, Folder 419)
        Thanking him for a copy of Beowulf
    - Lawrence, T.E. (Thomas Edward), 1888-1935
      - Photostatic copy of an ALS to Col. Ralph Isham, Dorset, 1935 May 10 (Box 9, Folder 420)
    - Lloyd, Charles, 1775-1839
      - AL to Charles Ollier, [London], [1820] (Box 9, Folder 421)
        Accompanied by a translation from La Motte-Fouqué entitled "Richard and Blondel, A Dramatic Idyll" Tinker 1501
    - Lyautey, Louis Hubert Gonslave, 1854-1934
      - ALS to Professor C.E. Andrews, [Maroc], [1922 Jul 15] (Box 9, Folder 422)
  - "M"
    - Macaulay, Thomas Babington Macaulay, Baron, 1800-1859
      - ALS to William Hickling Prescott, Kensington, 1859 Jan 8 (Box 9, Folder 423)
        Tinker 1508
    - Machen, Arthur, 1863-1947
      - ALS to Chauncey Brewster Tinker, 12 Melina Place, N.W.S., 1923 Sep 20 (Box 9, Folder 424)
        Thanking him for Tinker's Young Boswell
    - Marryat, Florence, 1837-1899
      - ALS to Mrs. Savory, London, 1897 Jul 5 (Box 9, Folder 425)
    - Martineau, Harriet, 1802-1876
      - AMS of a dialogue between "E." and "P." about the unregulated importation of corn, arguing for free trade as calculated to keep up the value of land, and critizing the Poor Laws (Box 9, Folder 426)
        Tinker 1527
    - Masefield, John, 1878-1967
      - ALS to Annie Elizabeth Fredericka Horniman, Great Hampden, Bucks, 1912 Aug 10 (Box 9, Folder 427)
        Tinker 1535
      - ALS to Annie Elizabeth Fredericka Horniman, Great Hampden, Bucks, 1912 Aug 15 (Box 9, Folder 428)
        Tinker 1536
      - ALS to Annie Elizabeth Fredericka Horniman, Great Hampden, Bucks, 1912 Aug 27 (Box 9, Folder 429)
        Tinker 1537
      - ALS to Annie Elizabeth Fredericka Horniman, Los Angeles, Calif., 1918 Mar 10 (Box 9, Folder 430)
        Tinker 1538
    - Meredith, George, 1828-1909
      - ALS to Albert Fleming, Box Hill, Dorking, 1885 Oct 8 (Box 9, Folder 431)
        Tinker 1546
      - ALS to R. MacLean, Box Hill, Dorking, 1889 Jun 27 (Box 9, Folder 432)
        Tinker 1547
    - Meynell, Alice Christiana Thompson, 1847-1922
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, London, [1898?] Nov 24 (Box 9, Folder 433)
        Tinker 1565
      - ANS to an unknown correspondent, Greatham Sussex, n.y. Jul 12 (Box 9, Folder 434)
        Tinker 1566
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified material
      - Miscellaneous engravings, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 435)
        Includes engravings of "Miss Ray", "Peter the Wild Boy", and "Mrs. Margaret Caroline Rudd"
      - Unidentified facsimile of a painting, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 436)
        2 copies
    - Mitford, Mary Russell, 1787-1855
      - 19 ALS to Charles Boner, 1845-49 (Box 9, Folder 437)
        Tinker 1577
      - 9 ALS to Barbara Hofland, 1817-19 Mar (Box 9, Folder 438)
        Tinker 1578
      - 11 ALS to Barbara Hofland, 1819 Apr 20 (Box 9, Folder 439)
      - 12 ALS to Barbara Hofland, 1821-24 (Box 10, Folder 440)
      - 10 ALS to Barbara Hofland, 1825-38 (Box 10, Folder 441)
      - 7 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1837-39 (Box 10, Folder 442)
        Tinker 1579
      - 5 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1840-41 Jul (Box 10, Folder 443)
      - 5 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1841 Oct-42 Feb (Box 10, Folder 444)
      - 6 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1842 Mar-Nov (Box 10, Folder 445)
      - 7 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1843-45 (Box 10, Folder 446)
      - 6 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1846 (Box 10, Folder 447)
      - 5 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1847 Jan-Aug (Box 10, Folder 448)
      - 5 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1847 Oct-1948 (Box 10, Folder 449)
      - 6 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1849-50 (Box 10, Folder 450)
      - 5 ALS to Mrs. William Edwards Partridge (née L. O. H. Anderdon), 1851, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 451)
        With one envelope postmarked [18]41 Oct 25 Tinker 1579
      - Sketch of Mrs. Partridge's life, in an unknown hand (Box 10, Folder 452)
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Three Mile Cross, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 453)
        Tinker 1580
      - Three watercolor drawings of Mitford's cottage at Three Mile Cross, Reading, Berkshire, England (Box 10, Folder 454)
        By an unidentified artist, on Whatman paper watermarked 1834
    - Montagu, Mary Wortley, Lady, 1689-1762
      - ALS to Frances Bettenson Hewet, York, [1713 Nov] (Box 10, Folder 455)
        Signed with initials. With a manuscript note above the address dated 1713 Nov 29 and signed "W. G." Tinker 1586
    - More, Hannah, 1745-1833
      - ALS to [Mrs. Hallyburton], Yoxall Lodge, Staffordshire, [1811] Aug 31 (Box 10, Folder 456)
        Tinker 1591
    - Morris, William, 1834-1896
      - AMS of "The Sleeve of Gold", and other poems (Box 10, Folder 457)
        Tinker 1595
      - AMS of "Cupid & Psyche", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 458)
        Tinker 1596
      - Illustrations for Cupid and Psyche, in The Earthly Paradise (Box 11, Folder 459)
        Tinker 1597
        See also: Oversize, Box 18, folder 642
      - AMS of "The relations of art to labour", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 460)
        Includes a cutting of fabric Tinker 1598
      - "The Lovers of Gudrun," poem, 1869 (Box 11, Folder 461)
        Proof sheets of The Earthly Paradise (London, 1868) renumbered by H. Buxton Forman, with corrections in his and others' hands. With bookplate and signature (January 1870) of Forman Tinker 1605
    - Murray, Alexander, 1775-1813
      - ALS to Sir Walter Scott, Urr, Kirkcudbrightshire, 1808 May 30 (Box 11, Folder 462)
        Tinker 1628
  - "N"
    - Newman, John Henry, 1801-1890
      - ALS to George Stanley Faber, Oriel College, Oxford, 1838 Apr 27 (Box 11, Folder 463)
        Tinker 1630
      - AN to Mr. Green, Birmingham, 1859 Oct 5 (Box 11, Folder 464)
        Tinker 1631
      - ALS to Francis Rivington, Littlemore, 1845 Apr 30 (Box 11, Folder 465)
        Tinker 1632
      - ALS (fragment) to Francis Rivington, Maryvale, Perry Bar, 1848 Mar 6 (Box 11, Folder 466)
        Tinker 1633
    - Nicholls, Norton, 1742?-1809
      - 3 ALS to William Johnston Temple, 1791-95 (Box 11, Folder 467)
  - "O"
    - O'Shaughnessy, Arthur William Edgar, 1844-1881
      - ALS to Mrs. Kroeker, Golborne Rd., Ladbroke Grove Rd., [1874 Dec 2] (Box 11, Folder 468)
        Tinker 1639
      - ALS to Mrs. Kroeker, 163 Golborne Rd., Notting Hill, 1876 Mar 2 (Box 11, Folder 469)
        Tinker 1640
  - "P"
    - Paoli, Pasquale, 1725-1807
      - ALS to Federico[?] Webb, London, 1801 May 18 (Box 11, Folder 470)
      - ALS to Sig. Abbate Politte, London, 1802 May 18 (Box 11, Folder 471)
    - Parker, M. E.
      - ALS to Robert Browning, London, 1878 Nov 9 (Box 11, Folder 472)
        With envelope. Manuscript attached to top of letter, possibly author's verse, corrected by Browning. Tinker 412
    - Pater, Clara
      - ALS to Mrs. R. W. Woodward, 6 Canning Place, Kensington, London, 1899 Feb 20 (Box 11, Folder 473)
        With envelope. Encloses two slips (one in English, one in Latin) containing notes made by Walter Pater. Tinker 1645
        See also: Box 7, folder 232
    - Patmore, Coventry, 1823-1896
      - ALS to H. Buxton Forman, Hastings, 1888 Oct 23 (Box 11, Folder 474)
        Tinker 1647
      - ALS to Frederic George Stephens, Hastings, 1889 Jun 2 (Box 11, Folder 475)
        Tinker 1648
    - Payne, John, d. 1787
      - Manuscript receipt, signed, to Messrs. Robert and James Dodsley, London, 1755 Dec 11 (Box 11, Folder 476)
        For 120 pounds "in full consideration for one half share of the copy-right of the Adventurer in four volumes duodecimo, [3rd ed., 1756] & all future impressions." Tinker 1416
    - Pepys, William Weller, Sir, 1740-1825
      - ALS (initials) to Hannah More, London, 1784 Dec 17 (Box 11, Folder 477)
        Tinker 1658
    - Percy, Thomas, 1729-1811
      - Autograph receipt, signed, to James Dodsley, 1763 Mar 25 (Box 11, Folder 478)
        For Percy's Miscellaneous Pieces Relating to the Chinese. On verso is earlier contract, signed by Dodsley, for the book, 1761 May 23. Tinker 1659
    - Phillips, R.
      See: Box 7, folder 269
    - Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821
      - Thraliana, negative photostatic reproductions, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 479)
        Selections from manuscripts in the Henry E. Huntington Library either by Piozzi, or about her.
      - ALS to Col. Henry Barry, Bath, 1789 Oct 19 (Box 11, Folder 480)
        Tinker 2145
      - ALS (initialled) to Sir James Fellowes, Bath, 1817 Mar 9 (Box 11, Folder 481)
    - Pitt, William, 1759-1806
      - LS to an unidentified member of Parliament, Downing Street, London, 1787 Jan 1 (Box 11, Folder 482)
        In an unidentified hand, probably that of a secretary. Tinker 1667
    - Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744
      - AMS (initials) of Preface to his Works, 1717, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 483)
        Tinker 1668
      - ANS to Martha Blount and Teresa Blount, [Chiswick], [1717 Oct 24] (Box 11, Folder 484)
        Tinker 1669
      - ALS to Dorothy Boyle, Countess of Burlington, [Twickenham?], [1732?] (Box 11, Folder 485)
        Tinker 1670
      - ALS to William Fortescue, [Twickenham?], [1730 Oct?] (Box 11, Folder 486)
        Tinker 1671
      - ALS to William Fortescue, [London], [1733 Jul?] (Box 11, Folder 487)
        Tinker 1672
      - ALS to William Fortescue, Twickenham, [1736 Apr 13] (Box 11, Folder 488)
        Tinker 1673
      - ALS to William Fortescue, [Twickenham], [1736 Jun] (Box 11, Folder 489)
        Tinker 1674
    - Pratt, Mr. (Samuel Jackson), 1749-1814
      - AL, signed C. Melmoth (pseud.) to Mr. [James] Dodsley, London, 1773 Dec 15 (Box 11, Folder 490)
        Tinker 1684
    - Psalmanazar, George, 1679?-1763
      - ALS to Samuel Reynolds, n.p., 1705/6 Feb 27 (Box 11, Folder 491)
        Tinker 1690
      - ALS to Samuel Reynolds, London, 1707 Jan 23 (Box 11, Folder 492)
        Tinker 1691
  - "Q"
    - Queen Anne
      - "Touch-piece", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 493)
  - "R"
    - Ramsay, Allan, 1713-1784
      - ALS to [John Stuart], London, 1762 Oct 28 (Box 11, Folder 494)
        Tinker 1707
    - Reade, Charles, 1814-1884
      - ANS to an unidentified recipient, Brighton, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 495)
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Brighton, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 496)
        Tinker 1710
    - Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792
      - Bound volume of sketches (Box 12, Folder 497)
      - Facsimile portrait, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 498)
    - Richardson, Jonathan, 1665-1745
      - Original pencil drawing of a boy's head from a statue by Alessandro Algardi, 1738 Jul 19 (Box 12, Folder 499)
    - Richardson, Samuel, 1689-1761
      - ALS to [Lady Echlin], London, 1756 Jun 22 (Box 12, Folder 500)
        Tinker 1732
      - Typed transcript of letter to Benjamin Kennicott, London, 1754 Nov 26 (Box 12, Folder 501)
        Original in possession of Chauncey Brewster Tinker
    - Rochester, Laurence Hyde, Earl of, 1641-1711
      - LS to Henry Hyde, Earl of Clarendon, Whitehall Treasury Chambers, 1686 Apr 20 (Box 12, Folder 502)
        Accompanied by portrait of the Earl of Rochester Tinker 1759
    - Rogers, Samuel, 1763-1855
      - AMS (initials) of "Verses written in Westminster Abbey...", 1807 Sep (Box 12, Folder 503)
        Tinker 1760
      - ANS to Mrs. Moxson, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 504)
    - Rossetti, Christina Georgina, 1830-1894
      - ALS to Ellen Heaton, London, [1894 Oct 13] (Box 12, Folder 505)
        With envelope. Accompanied by ALS from Earl Leslie Griggs to Chauncey Brewster Tinker, Duke University Station, Durham, N.C., 1939 Jul 31. Tinker 1774
      - ALS to Anne Gilchrist, London, 1865 Apr 17 (Box 12, Folder 506)
        Tinker 1772
      - ALS to Anne Gilchrist, London, 1882 Apr 27 (Box 12, Folder 507)
        Tinker 1773
      - ALS to Mrs. Amelia Heimann, London, [1874] (Box 12, Folder 508)
        Tinker 1775
      - ALS to Mrs. Amelia Heimann, [London], n.y. Feb 15 (Box 12, Folder 509)
        Tinker 1776
      - ALS to John H. Ingram, London, 1883 Apr 24 (Box 12, Folder 510)
        Tinker 1777
      - ALS to John H. Ingram, London, 1883 Apr 30 (Box 12, Folder 511)
        Tinker 1778
      - ALS to William Rossetti, London, [1891] (Box 12, Folder 512)
        Tinker 1779
      - AL to Edmund Clarence Stedman, London, 1869 Apr 7 (Box 12, Folder 513)
        Tinker 1780
      - ALS to [George Routledge and Sons?], London, 1873 Oct 4 (Box 12, Folder 514)
        Tinker 1781
      - ALS to "Dear Sir", London, 1892 Mar 7 (Box 12, Folder 515)
        Tinker 1782
      - ALS to an unknown correspondent, London, 1893 (Box 12, Folder 516)
        Tinker 1783
      - "A Bird Song," autograph manuscript, signed, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 517)
        Accompanied by a typescript. Tinker 1771
      - ALS from unidentified correspondent to CGR; "Memorial Sermon for the late Christina Georgina Rossetti," printed item (Box 12, Folder 518)
    - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882
      - AMS, verses, bound (Box 12, Folder 519)
        Cover title: "Sonnets by Dante Gabriel Rossetti" Tinker 1798
      - AMS of "Astarte Syriaca", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 520)
        Tinker 1799
      - AMS of "Ardour & Memory", 1879 (Box 12, Folder 521)
        Tinker 1800
      - AMS of "The White Ship", 1880 (Box 12, Folder 522)
        Tinker 1801
      - AMS of "The Cloud Confines", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 523)
        Tinker 1802
      - AMS of "Sonnet XCII-Michael Angelo's Kiss", n.d. (Box 12, Folder 524)
        Tinker 1803
      - ALS to Ford Madox Brown, [London], [1852 Dec 23] (Box 12, Folder 525)
        Tinker 1804
      - ANS to Ford Madox Brown, [London], [1871 Jul 29] (Box 12, Folder 526)
        Tinker 1805
      - ALS to [William] James Linton, London, 1862 Mar 12 (Box 12, Folder 527)
        Tinker 1806
      - ALS to William James Linton, Chelsea, 1866 Mar 2 (Box 12, Folder 528)
        Tinker 1807
      - [Ballads and sonnets, London], [1881] (Box 12, Folder 529)
        Tinker 1820
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900
      - ALS (initials) to "Darling Collie", Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire, 1886 Apr 14 (Box 12, Folder 530)
        Tinker 1834
      - ALS to Frederick Harris, Brantwood, Coniston, Lancs, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 531)
        Tinker 1835
      - ALS to Mr. O'Donohue, Tunbridge, n.y. May 31 (Box 12, Folder 532)
        Tinker 1836
      - ALS to Sir John Simon, Denmark Hill, 1869 Sep 6 (Box 12, Folder 533)
        Tinker 1837
      - ALS to W.J. Stillman, n.p., 1855 Oct 15 (Box 12, Folder 534)
        Tinker 1838
    - Rutland, John Henry Manners, Duke of, 1778-1857
      - ALS to [George Crabbe, Jr.], Belvoir Castle, 1832 Feb 7 (Box 12, Folder 535)
        Tinker 793
  - "S"
    - Sayers, Dorothy L. (Dorothy Leigh), 1893-1957
      - ALS to J. [Milkman?], London, 1929 Nov 29 (Box 12, Folder 536)
    - Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832
      - ALS to Sir Samuel Egerton Brydges, Edinburgh, [1808] Feb 20 (Box 12, Folder 537)
        Tinker 1858
      - ALS to Miss Wagner of Liverpool, Edinburgh, [1828] Feb 7 (Box 12, Folder 538)
        Tinker 1859
    - Shenstone, William, 1714-1763
      - ALS to J[oseph] C[ockfield], The Leasowes, 1761 Sep 17 (Box 12, Folder 539)
        Tinker 1909
      - ALS to an unidentified recipient, Halesowen, Worcs., 1758 Jun 27 (Box 12, Folder 540)